Guide to the Shaun Maloney Papers
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
- Shaun Maloney papers, 1932-2000; 5255-001; 35.08 cu. ft. (37 units); 261 sound cassette tapes; 10 videocassettes (VHS); 1 sound tape reel; 7 sound cassette tapes (microcassettes)
  - International Longshoremen's And Warehousemen's Union (Post Retirement)
    - Subject Series
      - Seattle World Class Port Coalition, 1998 (Box-folder 28/49)
      - Straddle 6, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 28/50)
      - Straddle 6 Beef, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 28/51)
      - Summary on Kagel re: Rules 4, 1976, 1981 (Box-folder 28/52)
      - Van Dyke, Gretchen, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 28/53-54)
    - Indices of Arbitrator Decisions, 1976-1995 (Box-folder 28/55-59)
    - Reports, 1980-1997, n.d. (Box-folder 29/1-8)
    - Invoices, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 29/9)
    - Financial Reports, 1978-1996 (Box-folder 29/10-14)
    - Administrative Decisions, 1988, 1994 (Box-folder 29/15-16)
    - Elections, 1976-1997; Includes oversized. (Box-folder 29/17-18)
    - Directories, n.d. (Box-folder 29/19)
    - Transcripts (of Proceedings)
      - APL Arbitration, 1979 (Box-folder 29/20)
      - Arbitration-Campbell v. PMA & ILWU, 1991 (Box-folder 29/21)
      - Arbitration-G.P. #1372, 1995 (Box-folder 29/22)
      - Arbitration-ILWU v. PMA, 1990 (Box-folder 29/23)
      - Arbitration-ILWU v. PMA, 1997 (Box-folder 29/24)
      - Arbitration-ILWU v. PMA, 1995 (Box-folder 29/25)
      - Caucus 1981 (Box-folder 29/26)
      - Class B Depo[sition]s, n.d. (Box-folder 29/27)
      - Deposition of Pat Vukich, 1996 (Box-folder 29/28)
      - Grievance Hearing-G.P. #1372, 1995 (Box-folder 29/29)
      - SLJPLRC Meeting Frazier Grievance, 1993 (Box-folder 29/30)
      - Walker, Eddie, Dep[osition], n.d. (Box-folder 29/31)
    - Court Papers, 1974-1998 (Box-folder 29/32-44)
    - Speeches and Writings of Others
      - Brown, Archie and Lima, Albert (Box-folder 29/45)
      - Hatch, Will, n.d. (Box-folder 29/46)
      - Hanson, Ron, 1995 (Box-folder 29/47)
      - Herman, Jim, 1979, 1990 (Box-folder 29/48-49)
      - Injured Workers United, n.d. (Box-folder 29/50)
      - Institute of the North American West, 1991 (Box-folder 29/51)
      - Kagel, Sam, 1995 (Box-folder 29/52)
      - Leonard, Norman, 1967 (Box-folder 29/53)
      - McWilliams, Brian, 1995 (Box-folder 29/54)
      - Mills, Herb, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 29/55-56)
      - Munson, John, 1986-1996 (Box-folder 29/57)
      - Nelson, Bruce, n.d. (Box-folder 29/58)
      - Parks, G. Johnny, 1981 (Box-folder 29/59)
      - Plant, T.G., 1940 (Box-folder 29/60)
      - Report from Spain, 1984 (Box-folder 29/61)
      - Seattle Casual Checkers Association, 1978 (Box-folder 29/62)
      - Authors Unknown, n.d. (Box-folder 29/63)
    - Newsletters, 1975-1998, n.d. (Box-folder 29/64-78)
    - Drawings, n.d. (Box-folder 30/1)
    - Publications
      - "Electing Union Officers", 1993 (Box-folder 30/2)
      - ILUW Miscellaneous, 1976-1997 (Box-folder 30/3)
      - Seattle Longshore Centennial, 1986 (Box-folder 30/4)
      - ILWU Calendar, 1987 (Box-folder 30/5)
    - Petitions, 1979, n.d. (Box-folder 30/6-7)
    - Resolutions, 1981-1998, n.d. (Box-folder 30/8-10)
    - Grievances, 1976-1997, n.d. (Box-folder 30/11)
    - News Releases, 1979-1996 (Box-folder 30/12)
    - Negotiations, 1991, 1996 (Box-folder 30/13)
    - Legislation, 1977, 1994 (Box-folder 30/14)
    - Flyers, 1977-1998, n.d. (Box-folder 30/15-18)
    - Notes, 1986-1997, n.d. (Box-folder 30/19-48)
    - Drafts, 1977-1997, n.d. (Box-folder 30/49-71)
    - Drafts, 1977-1997, n.d. (Box-folder 31/1-21)
    - Clippings, 1958-1997, n.d. (Box-folder 31/22-25)
    - Ephemera, 1984-1996, n.d. (Box-folder 31/26)
    - Miscellany, 1983-1996, n.d. (Box-folder 31/27-28)
    - Pacific Coast Pensioners Association
      - Minutes, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 31/29-30)
      - Conference and Convention Files, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 31/31-32)
      - Newsletters, 1993-1998 (Box-folder 31/33-35)
      - Miscellany, 1976-1997 (Box-folder 31/36)
  - Gordon, Rose Mary Meecham
    - Transcripts (of Interviews), 1988, 2000 (Box-folder 31/37-41)
    - Audio Cassette Tapes, 1999 (Box-folder 31/42)
  - Videotapes
    - Marine Workers' Historical Association Oral History Interview with Maloney, Parts 1 & 2, 1991 (Box-folder 32)
    - No Mob Rule - 1996 Teamster Convention (Box-folder 32)
    - (ILWU) International Executive Board Meeting, 1991 (Box-folder 32)
    - 2nd Year Bridges Chair (Box-folder 32)
    - Waterfront Soundings Conference vol. 2, 1991; Two copies. (Box-folder 32)
    - We Are the ILWU, n.d. (Box-folder 32)
    - HBI [Harry Bridges Institute], History of, n.d. (Box-folder 32)
    - National Conference of Black Lawyers - Thomas Nomination, 1991
  - Audio Cassette Tapes (Box-folder 34-36)
    Listen to select interviews on the Libraries Digital Collections site.
- Transcript of an oral history interview with Shaun Maloney, May 30-August 23, 1979; 5255-002; .21 cubic foot 1 box
  Interview conducted May 30-August 23, 1979 by Chris Miller and partly by Martin Duffy, apparently by telephone between St. Paul, MN and Seattle, WA. Also includes copies of historical papers, notes, and written questions and responses.
  Maloney discusses the Minneapolis Teamsters strike of 1934 and how he became involved in the labor movement.
  Copy of original in Shaun Maloney Union Activism Papers, Minnesota Historical Society, St. Paul, MN.
- Shaun Maloney papers, 1886-2000; 5255-003; 1.81 cubic feet 2 boxes
  Booklets, ephemera, contracts, and other materials collected by Maloney on several areas he was interested in. Topics include the International Longshore and Warehouse Union, the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Correspondence between Maloney within his union and with external correspondents comprise another portion of this collection. Patches and buttons of labor and political issues are part of this collection. The collection contains news clippings on Minnesota and Minneapolis labor in the 1930s. Maloney was a Teamster leader during the Minneapolis-St. Paul general strike in 1934, and later participated in history projects and did his own research on the era.
  No restrictions on access.
  Donated by Rita Shaw, signed for by Joan Sandler, 2016.
  - Booklets, 1928-1996; Series 1
    - Misc. International Longshore's and Warehousemen's Union + Dockworkers, 1952-1987 (Box-folder 1/1-2)
    - ILWU Constitution, 1947-1994 (Box-folder 1/3-4)
    - Pacific Coast Longshore Contracts, 1966-1996 (Box-folder 1/5-7)
    - Teamster Agreements, 1964-1982 (Box-folder 1/8-10)
    - PCL Agreements, 1947-1966 (Box-folder 1/11-12)
    - Mixed Agreements, 1941-1996 (Box-folder 1/13-15)
    - Misc. Labor Agreements and Unemployment Compensation Law, 1937-1976 (Box-folder 1/16)
    - Court Cases - Maloney, 1934 and 1956 (Box-folder 1/17)
    - Address books, travel guides, and phonebook, 1938 (Box-folder 1/18)
    - Sunday Missal, 1941 (Box-folder 1/19)
    - Pacific Coast Marine Safety Code, 1931-1996 (Box-folder 1/20-2/1)
    - Safety Regulations and OSHA Longshore, 1960-1975 (Box-folder 2/2-3)
  - Articles, Documents, and Newspaper Clippings, 1928-2000; Series 2
    - Misc. Photographs, 1928-1973 (Box-folder 2/4)
    - On-Going Notes on Shipping, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 2/5)
    - ILWU and Maritime Article Copies, 1937-1975 (Box-folder 2/6)
    - Misc. Correspondence, 1988 (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Minnesota's Labor Movement and Related Articles, 1984-1988 (Box-folder 2/8)
    - Minneapolis Newspaper Clippings and Copies, 1930's and 1984 (Box-folder 2/9)
    - Various Teamster Articles, 1966, 1986, 1988 (Box-folder 2/10)
    - University of Washington Archive Correspondence, 2000 (Box-folder 2/11)
    - Shaun Maloney's Estate, 2000 (Box-folder 2/12)
    - Shaun "Jack" Maloney's Memorial, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 2/13)
    - Internal Letters and Documents, 1961, 1983, 1998 (Box-folder 2/14)
    - Memorabilia and a Family Letter, 1965; 1986 (Box-folder 2/15)
  - Memorabilia, 1886-1996; Series 3
    - Union Patches, Sticker, Membership card and business card, 1971 (Box-folder 2/16)
    - Labor related pinback buttons, 1886-1996 (Box-folder 2/17)
    - Labor related pinback buttons and two bullets, 1956-1976 (Box-folder 2/18)